# **Aoxuan Wang**

Phone: +44 7784632025 | +86 13720049459

E-mail: aoxuan.wang@outlook.com linkedin.com/in/aoxuan-wang-5a74441b9

# **PROFILE**

A postgraduate student of Banking and Risk with machine learning knowledge. Have strong learning ability and financial data knowledge, passed CFA level 2 and all ACCA tests, all by self-study. Experienced in multicultural environment communication and team working with different background persons and like to face and learn any new knowledge. Have strong analytical, numerical skills, and perform well under pressure

#### **EDUCATION**

# The University of Edinburgh (Masters)

09/2021 - 08/2022

MSc Banking and Risk

The dissertation is about Financial Machine Learning - using neural network models , such as XGBoost and AutoGluon, to analyse American Option valuation.

 Learned knowledge in the background of data mining and financial machine learning, and used different methods to analysis business cases, including SVM, Random forest, Neural Network, LDA&QDA, KNN, K-means, and so on

# **Beijing University of Technology (UG)**

09/2017 - 07/2021

Bachelor's in Finance - GPA 3.8/4.0

The dissertation is about the spillover effect between China's and US's stock markets under COVID-19 circumstance, via STATA and time series model to analyse the relationship of two markets' data.

- Scholarship for Best Learner (critical on academic scores)
- Possessing financial analysis ability, including cash flow discount analysis, price multiple analysis, technique analysis and so on. Won the First Place in HK and US Stock Investment Competition
- Data processing and IT ability, including STATA, SPSS, Python
- College Students Mathematical Modelling Contest, as the Team Leader, led the team to solve the heat conduction problem of firefighters' fire suits, coordinated and completed data visualisation and final paper completion, and led the team members to consult thermodynamic formulas and analysed heat conduction laws, arranged meetings regularly to ensure the progress of review team and calculation team. Finally, utilised Stata to visualise the results obtained and used LaTeX to complete a 3000 words essay

# Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (Summer Exchange)

2019

Bloomberg Finance Practical Training Camp

 Participated Bloomberg Terminal skills via evaluating stocks, bonds, foreign currencies, and derivatives

# **Tokyo University (Summer Exchange)**

2018

Sociology, as well as some cutting-edge technology of Japan

- Conducted a face-to-face conversation with the professor and gaining in-depth knowledge about Japanese politics and social culture, and then wrote a news report of it for the university official WeChat blog
- Participated in lectures and field trips to learn Japan's unique economic structure and cuttingedge technology, getting an international culture realisation

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### **Huachuang Security (Intern)**

07/2020 - 08/2020

Fixed-income Department, Credit Risk of Urban Construction Investment Co. in China

#### **Assistant**

- Collaborated with my team to collect more than 50 Urban Construction Investment Companies' financial reports, extracted important paragraphs and arguments, assisted those data, and prepared a monthly report
- Collected and calculated financial data, by Excel, and assisting my team in the completion of the data spreadsheet including more the 20 sheets, to support the further analysis

# China Communications Materials & Equipment Company Limit (Intern)

05/2020 - 07/2020

Subsidiary of China Communications Construction (Global 500, ranking 78th)

# **Accounting Assistant**

- Coordinated the relationship of other subsidiaries by assisting my manager, including 3 suppliers and customers, about the goods delivery and trade receivable
- Dealt with detail accounting papers and recorded accounting data through the ERP system

# Research Institute of Machinery Industry Economic& Management (Intern) 12/2019 – 04/2020 Wind Power Project Team

#### **Data Assistant**

- Business analysis about the wind power market. Conducted the significance analysis of
  influencing factors and analysed the collinearity and autocorrelation issues in the model by
  using Stata, to predict the prospects of the wind power market, including adopting logistic curve
  to fit the 7-year development data of market
- Addressed a short presentation of my calculation and opinion of the wind power industry to my team numbers, and then held a brainstorm discussion with them to find the drivers of market

# Department of Wise China Magazine

#### **Research Assistant**

- Writing skills in engaging in composing a paper in this magazine, the Opinion on the Operation Mechanism of Supply Chain Finance and Risk Prevention and Resolution. Knowing academic research and writing framework
- Presentation ability. Preformed and then presented a articles review. Read more than 100 papers to summarise the current situation and pain points of supply chain finance, as well as the characteristics and trends of the development of blockchain technology, and proposed solutions. Time management ability practiced in reading and taking notes for those papers

## **THESIS WRITING**

 The mechanism of supply chain finance operation and risk prevention and resolution - Wise China Magazine, 2021

## **ADDITIONAL SKILLS AND ACHIEVEMENTS**

Languages: English (fluent, IELTS 7.5), Chinese (native), Japanese (Daily conversational),

Latin &.Greek (introductory level)

Certificates: ACCA (passed all tests), CFA level 2 passed, Bloomberg Certificate

I.T. Skills: Python, SPSS, STATA, R, SAS, Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel), LaTeX, HTML

Hobbies and Interests: fitness (Powerlifting), cycling, history, language learning

**University Involvement:** Military Art Clubs (Organized the recruiting and roadshow activities for the new students in my junior year, and the recruiting activities were successfully completed)